<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog &#8211; x-SITE</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/category/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:51:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/favicon.png</url>
	<title>Blog &#8211; x-SITE</title>
	<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>So we saw some sharks…</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/so-we-saw-some-sharks/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/so-we-saw-some-sharks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our incredible shark adventure started out with some weather delays but once we got on-sitethere was plenty of shark action. We saw multiple Tiger Sharks and hammerheads on each dive,in addition, there were, Bull, Lemon, Caribbean Reef, and Nurse Sharks in attendance. The boataccommodations and crew were outstanding, and tasty food, and a really entertaining [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Our incredible shark adventure started out with some weather delays but once we got on-site<br>there was plenty of shark action. We saw multiple Tiger Sharks and hammerheads on each dive,<br>in addition, there were, Bull, Lemon, Caribbean Reef, and Nurse Sharks in attendance. The boat<br>accommodations and crew were outstanding, and tasty food, and a really entertaining group of<br>people made for a wonderful trip. This was our honeymoon trip and what an experience, it is<br>one that we will never forget. The crew made sure we always felt comfortable and treated us<br>like family. We just booked our next trip, humpback whales – can’t wait!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/so-we-saw-some-sharks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>elly, jelly, jelly</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/elly-jelly-jelly/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/elly-jelly-jelly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ What can we say about jellyfish? These squishy, jellylike creatures pulse along on 
ocean currents and are abundant in both cold and warm ocean water, in deep water, and along 
coastlines. They have no blood, brains, or a heart yet they are still an invertebrate.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Jellyfish are one of the most beautiful creatures in the sea</h2>



<p>Nothing is more mesmerizing than watching a jellyfish travel through the ocean, they move like<br>no other creature. A jellyfish is an aquatic animal, they can be found in just about every sea in<br>the world, even the arctic ocean, and some jellies that live in freshwater environments. They<br>are invertebrates that have no skeleton. Jellyfish squirt water from their mouths to propel<br>themselves forward. Jellyfish have nerve nets instead of brains, which sense changes in their<br>environment. Jellyfish can be identified by the tentacles that hang down from their bodies,<br>some have short and others have very long tentacles. What do they munch on? They eat small<br>fish, fish eggs, shrimp, and plankton .</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cool jelly facts:</h3>



<p>A large number of jellyfish is called a bloom, some blooms contain over 500 million<br>jellyfish!</p>



<ul>
<li>Some jellyfish can be as large as a refrigerator</li>



<li>Jellyfish can clone themselves, yup that’s right, if a jellyfish is cut in half it can actually<br>regenerate its body.</li>



<li>Some jellies glow in the dark to attract prey</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="400" height="600" data-id="92"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-jelly02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-92"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="400" height="600" data-id="91"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-jelly01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-91"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/elly-jelly-jelly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sharks are not evil, senseless killers</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/sharks-are-not-evil-senseless-killers/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/sharks-are-not-evil-senseless-killers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[it is estimated that 100 million sharks are killed by humans every year, that is about 200 sharks 
per minute, 3 sharks a second. Humans are driving sharks to the brink of extinction at 
unsustainable rates. By removing sharks from the ocean we threaten a much wider diversity of 
life.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It is estimated that 100 million sharks are killed by humans every year, that is about 200 sharks<br>per minute, 3 sharks a second. Humans are driving sharks to the brink of extinction at<br>unsustainable rates. By removing sharks from the ocean we threaten a much wider diversity of<br>life.<br>Our oceans need sharks, they are an integral part of the ecosystem, they directly affect the<br>food web and help maintain a healthy ocean ecosystem. For instance, without sharks’ turtles do<br>not move around as much and overgraze in a few locations which quickly destroys these<br>important habitats for many fish, shellfish, and birds. Without sharks, there is an increase of<br>smaller fish that prey on herbivorous fish that graze on algae. With an overgrowth of algae on<br>coral reefs coral growth and biodiversity decrease the resilience of the reef. Sharks help<br>support healthy seagrass meadows by preventing overgrazing and therefore play an important<br>role in the carbon cycle. Seagrass absorbs lots of carbon preventing greenhouse gases from the<br>atmosphere. And sharks help eliminate sick and unhealthy fish from ocean populations, they<br>prey on weaker animals which in turn ensures that the ones that survive and reproduce are the<br>stronger and more healthy fish.<br>Shark finning is decimating the shark population. This gruesome practice of cutting off the<br>shark’s fins and throwing the live animal back into the sea where it dies a slow and painful<br>death. The demand for the status symbol of shark fin soup is driving this craze and the ripple<br>effects are impacting all areas of the ocean. With their slow growth and low reproductive rates,<br>sharks are highly susceptible to extinction, and it is difficult for many shark species to replenish<br>their populations as quickly as they are being diminished. Many species are currently in danger<br>and most have populations that are vulnerable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/sharks-are-not-evil-senseless-killers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All-time best experience</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/all-time-best-experience/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/all-time-best-experience/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can’t even properly explain what we experienced on this trip, we saw so much sea life, it wastruly incredible. The Great Barrier reef trip is the way to experience this world wonder.Almost three months have passed since our grand adventure with MAR, and a day hasn’tpassed where we don’t talk about the amazing time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I can’t even properly explain what we experienced on this trip, we saw so much sea life, it was<br>truly incredible. The Great Barrier reef trip is the way to experience this world wonder.<br>Almost three months have passed since our grand adventure with MAR, and a day hasn’t<br>passed where we don’t talk about the amazing time we had. The entire trip was organized to<br>give us the best opportunities of seeing as many of the animals that we had all come to see,<br>and it did not disappoint. I would not hesitate to book another trip with the MAR crew. It was<br>as if we were holidaying with old friends. Thank you MAR!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-3 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="89"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-allTime03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="88"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-allTime02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-88"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="286" height="400" data-id="87"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-allTime01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-87"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/all-time-best-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Octopuses – aliens among us!</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/octopuses-aliens-among-us/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/octopuses-aliens-among-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Known for their otherworldly, alienish look and incredible intelligence, octopuses 
continue to reveal astonishing qualities, abilities and behaviors.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Octopuses are one of the most fascinating creatures</h2>



<p>The octopus is probably one of the most fascinating ocean creatures, they have 8 arms, a<br>bulbous head, and are super intelligent. They are boneless and can squeeze in and out of really<br>tight spaces, they have 3 hearts, blue blood, and 9 brains. They can squirt ink, use tools and<br>instantly change colors and textures. Basically, they are endlessly fascinating.<br>Octopuses come in many sizes, the smallest species is smaller than an inch while the giant<br>pacific octopus can easily grow to be 16 feet long and weigh around 100 pounds. The largest on<br>record was more than 30 feet in length and came in at a whopping 600 pounds. Octopuses live<br>in oceans all over the world but most live near shores and on reefs.<br>One of the coolest things about octopuses is their ability to change color and texture.<br>Octopuses alter their color to hide and match their surroundings. They can turn blue, gray, red,<br>pink, brown or green. Some are able to flex their bodies to resemble more dangerous animals,<br>such as eels and lionfish, and many can change the texture of their skin from smooth to bumpy.<br>They are able to swim by sucking water into their bodies and then shoot it out of their siphons<br>which allows them to blast away from predators, but many prefer to ‘walk’ or crawl along the<br>seafloor. I have observed an octopus changing its color and texture to mimic kelp where it is<br>difficult to tell the difference between the two.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Here are some cool things about octopuses:</h3>



<ul>
<li>Octopuses have been observed using tools</li>



<li>They can change the color of their body in 3/10’s of a second</li>



<li>Their suckers are really strong, each sucker can live at least 20x its weight and on<br>average, each arm has 240 suckers</li>



<li>All octopuses contain venom but only the blue-ringed octopus has enough to paralyze<br>an adult in a number of seconds.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-5 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="98"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo05.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-98"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="97"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo04.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-97"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="96"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-96"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="401" data-id="95"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-95"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="94"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-94"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/octopuses-aliens-among-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
