<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>x-SITE</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 19:08:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/favicon.png</url>
	<title>x-SITE</title>
	<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>So we saw some sharks…</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/so-we-saw-some-sharks/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/so-we-saw-some-sharks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our incredible shark adventure started out with some weather delays but once we got on-sitethere was plenty of shark action. We saw multiple Tiger Sharks and hammerheads on each dive,in addition, there were, Bull, Lemon, Caribbean Reef, and Nurse Sharks in attendance. The boataccommodations and crew were outstanding, and tasty food, and a really entertaining [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Our incredible shark adventure started out with some weather delays but once we got on-site<br>there was plenty of shark action. We saw multiple Tiger Sharks and hammerheads on each dive,<br>in addition, there were, Bull, Lemon, Caribbean Reef, and Nurse Sharks in attendance. The boat<br>accommodations and crew were outstanding, and tasty food, and a really entertaining group of<br>people made for a wonderful trip. This was our honeymoon trip and what an experience, it is<br>one that we will never forget. The crew made sure we always felt comfortable and treated us<br>like family. We just booked our next trip, humpback whales – can’t wait!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/so-we-saw-some-sharks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>elly, jelly, jelly</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/elly-jelly-jelly/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/elly-jelly-jelly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ What can we say about jellyfish? These squishy, jellylike creatures pulse along on 
ocean currents and are abundant in both cold and warm ocean water, in deep water, and along 
coastlines. They have no blood, brains, or a heart yet they are still an invertebrate.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Jellyfish are one of the most beautiful creatures in the sea</h2>



<p>Nothing is more mesmerizing than watching a jellyfish travel through the ocean, they move like<br>no other creature. A jellyfish is an aquatic animal, they can be found in just about every sea in<br>the world, even the arctic ocean, and some jellies that live in freshwater environments. They<br>are invertebrates that have no skeleton. Jellyfish squirt water from their mouths to propel<br>themselves forward. Jellyfish have nerve nets instead of brains, which sense changes in their<br>environment. Jellyfish can be identified by the tentacles that hang down from their bodies,<br>some have short and others have very long tentacles. What do they munch on? They eat small<br>fish, fish eggs, shrimp, and plankton .</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cool jelly facts:</h3>



<p>A large number of jellyfish is called a bloom, some blooms contain over 500 million<br>jellyfish!</p>



<ul>
<li>Some jellyfish can be as large as a refrigerator</li>



<li>Jellyfish can clone themselves, yup that’s right, if a jellyfish is cut in half it can actually<br>regenerate its body.</li>



<li>Some jellies glow in the dark to attract prey</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="400" height="600" data-id="92"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-jelly02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-92"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="400" height="600" data-id="91"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-jelly01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-91"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/elly-jelly-jelly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sharks are not evil, senseless killers</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/sharks-are-not-evil-senseless-killers/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/sharks-are-not-evil-senseless-killers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[it is estimated that 100 million sharks are killed by humans every year, that is about 200 sharks 
per minute, 3 sharks a second. Humans are driving sharks to the brink of extinction at 
unsustainable rates. By removing sharks from the ocean we threaten a much wider diversity of 
life.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It is estimated that 100 million sharks are killed by humans every year, that is about 200 sharks<br>per minute, 3 sharks a second. Humans are driving sharks to the brink of extinction at<br>unsustainable rates. By removing sharks from the ocean we threaten a much wider diversity of<br>life.<br>Our oceans need sharks, they are an integral part of the ecosystem, they directly affect the<br>food web and help maintain a healthy ocean ecosystem. For instance, without sharks’ turtles do<br>not move around as much and overgraze in a few locations which quickly destroys these<br>important habitats for many fish, shellfish, and birds. Without sharks, there is an increase of<br>smaller fish that prey on herbivorous fish that graze on algae. With an overgrowth of algae on<br>coral reefs coral growth and biodiversity decrease the resilience of the reef. Sharks help<br>support healthy seagrass meadows by preventing overgrazing and therefore play an important<br>role in the carbon cycle. Seagrass absorbs lots of carbon preventing greenhouse gases from the<br>atmosphere. And sharks help eliminate sick and unhealthy fish from ocean populations, they<br>prey on weaker animals which in turn ensures that the ones that survive and reproduce are the<br>stronger and more healthy fish.<br>Shark finning is decimating the shark population. This gruesome practice of cutting off the<br>shark’s fins and throwing the live animal back into the sea where it dies a slow and painful<br>death. The demand for the status symbol of shark fin soup is driving this craze and the ripple<br>effects are impacting all areas of the ocean. With their slow growth and low reproductive rates,<br>sharks are highly susceptible to extinction, and it is difficult for many shark species to replenish<br>their populations as quickly as they are being diminished. Many species are currently in danger<br>and most have populations that are vulnerable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/sharks-are-not-evil-senseless-killers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All-time best experience</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/all-time-best-experience/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/all-time-best-experience/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can’t even properly explain what we experienced on this trip, we saw so much sea life, it wastruly incredible. The Great Barrier reef trip is the way to experience this world wonder.Almost three months have passed since our grand adventure with MAR, and a day hasn’tpassed where we don’t talk about the amazing time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I can’t even properly explain what we experienced on this trip, we saw so much sea life, it was<br>truly incredible. The Great Barrier reef trip is the way to experience this world wonder.<br>Almost three months have passed since our grand adventure with MAR, and a day hasn’t<br>passed where we don’t talk about the amazing time we had. The entire trip was organized to<br>give us the best opportunities of seeing as many of the animals that we had all come to see,<br>and it did not disappoint. I would not hesitate to book another trip with the MAR crew. It was<br>as if we were holidaying with old friends. Thank you MAR!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-3 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="89"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-allTime03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="88"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-allTime02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-88"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="286" height="400" data-id="87"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-allTime01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-87"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/all-time-best-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Octopuses – aliens among us!</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/octopuses-aliens-among-us/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/octopuses-aliens-among-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Known for their otherworldly, alienish look and incredible intelligence, octopuses 
continue to reveal astonishing qualities, abilities and behaviors.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Octopuses are one of the most fascinating creatures</h2>



<p>The octopus is probably one of the most fascinating ocean creatures, they have 8 arms, a<br>bulbous head, and are super intelligent. They are boneless and can squeeze in and out of really<br>tight spaces, they have 3 hearts, blue blood, and 9 brains. They can squirt ink, use tools and<br>instantly change colors and textures. Basically, they are endlessly fascinating.<br>Octopuses come in many sizes, the smallest species is smaller than an inch while the giant<br>pacific octopus can easily grow to be 16 feet long and weigh around 100 pounds. The largest on<br>record was more than 30 feet in length and came in at a whopping 600 pounds. Octopuses live<br>in oceans all over the world but most live near shores and on reefs.<br>One of the coolest things about octopuses is their ability to change color and texture.<br>Octopuses alter their color to hide and match their surroundings. They can turn blue, gray, red,<br>pink, brown or green. Some are able to flex their bodies to resemble more dangerous animals,<br>such as eels and lionfish, and many can change the texture of their skin from smooth to bumpy.<br>They are able to swim by sucking water into their bodies and then shoot it out of their siphons<br>which allows them to blast away from predators, but many prefer to ‘walk’ or crawl along the<br>seafloor. I have observed an octopus changing its color and texture to mimic kelp where it is<br>difficult to tell the difference between the two.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Here are some cool things about octopuses:</h3>



<ul>
<li>Octopuses have been observed using tools</li>



<li>They can change the color of their body in 3/10’s of a second</li>



<li>Their suckers are really strong, each sucker can live at least 20x its weight and on<br>average, each arm has 240 suckers</li>



<li>All octopuses contain venom but only the blue-ringed octopus has enough to paralyze<br>an adult in a number of seconds.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-5 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="98"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo05.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-98"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="97"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo04.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-97"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="96"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-96"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="401" data-id="95"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-95"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="94"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-blog-octo01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-94"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/octopuses-aliens-among-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shark Finning</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-finning/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-finning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Our apex predators, like sharks, play a critical role in regulating the eco-system - and 
they need our help! Many sharks are brutally slaughtered every day due to the inhuman 
process of finning. A third of shark species are already threatened with extinction.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Shark finning: a brutal practice</h2>



<p>Each year, millions of sharks are hunted down, only to have their fins sliced off and their bodies<br>are thrown back into the ocean often left to die an agonizing death. A shark is caught, pulled<br>onboard a boat, its fins are cut off, and the still-living shark is tossed back overboard to drown<br>or bleed to death. The wasteful, inhumane practice is done to satisfy a demand for shark fins,<br>which are in high demand for a luxury soup in Asia with reputable medicinal properties.<br>It has been proven that the shark fins have no nutritional value and are basically tasteless, the<br>flavor of the soup is derived from the broth. The fins are simply added for novelty and status</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is the threat to sharks?</h3>



<p>Finning is responsible for the death of about 100 million sharks every year, that is about 2-3<br>sharks being brutally killed every second! The exact numbers are unknown because in many<br>places and hauls aren’t accurately counted since shark finning is illegal.<br>Because sharks are at the top of the food chain and have few predators, they reproduce and<br>mature slowly. That means their numbers are slow to replenish when a population is<br>overfished. At the rate humans are going, we’re set to wipe out sharks entirely in as little as a<br>decade or so.<br>If sharks are completely eliminated we will have serious problems. Sharks are apex predators<br>and as such, they are invaluable for keeping the populations of everything else in the food chain<br>in balance. The oceans depend on sharks to keep the numbers of other fish and mammal<br>species in check by weeding out the sick, injured, and dying so that populations of fish stay<br>strong and healthy. Without sharks, the balance of the ocean’s food chain is in serious<br>jeopardy.<br>Shark finning is a cruel and dangerous practice, these vital animals are necessary to the<br>ecological balance of our oceans and are about to be wiped out completely</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What can you do?</h3>



<p>Educate yourself and others about how important sharks are</p>



<ul>
<li>Help spread the word about finning</li>



<li>Avoid all shark-related products and boycott businesses that sell and serve shark fins</li>



<li>Support marine protected areas</li>



<li>Urge your senator to support and pass the Shark Fin Sales Elimination Act of 2019<br>Sharks deserve to be swim free and are a vital part of the ocean ecosystem. Speak up for those<br>who can’t!</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-7 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="399" data-id="107"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-finning03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-107"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="106"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-finning02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-106"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="105"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-finning01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-105"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="397" data-id="108"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-finning04.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-108"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-finning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We have a plastic problem</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/we-have-a-plastic-problem/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/we-have-a-plastic-problem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our oceans are facing growing challenges from pollution, habitat loss, development, 
and climate change.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Plastics are everyone’s problem</h2>



<p>Our oceans are facing growing challenges from pollution, habitat loss, development, and<br>climate change. The impact of plastic and micro-plastics on our seas is outrageous and<br>devastating for many species. Learn more about what you can do to stop it.<br>The ocean downstream from nearly every terrestrial location, it is the receiving body for much<br>of the plastic waste generated on land. Several million tons of debris end up in the world’s<br>oceans every year, and much of it is improperly discarded plastic litter.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Here are just a few chilling facts:</h3>



<ul>
<li>It is estimated that by 2050, oceans will carry more plastic mass than fish</li>



<li>Plastic waste kills up to 1 million sea birds, 100,000 sea mammals, marine turtles, and<br>countless fish each year</li>



<li>80% of all pollution in seas and oceans comes from land-based activities</li>



<li>It’s not just animals: people are consuming microplastics too. Ewwww!</li>



<li>A garbage truck’s worth of plastic is dumped into the ocean every single minute</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Take action right now!</h3>



<p>For a healthy planet, we need healthy oceans. Oceans cover 70% of the earth’s surface and they<br>are seriously under threat. We all need to do our part. Here are some things you can do right<br>now:</p>



<ul>
<li>Refuse single-use plastics</li>



<li>Only consume sustainable seafood</li>



<li>Speak up! Contact your representatives and let them know you are concerned.<br>The world is changing and finding a sustainable balance between the planet, people and profit<br>is challenging. Our vision is to raise awareness, encouraging more sustainable approaches and<br>choices. We need to help protect this fascinating environment and all the life that depends on it<br>to survive. Be the change, educate yourself and make smart choices, support businesses that<br>provide sustainable experiences and harvesting. Protect what you love!<br>We need everyone to help fight the plastic problem. Start now, before it’s too late.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-9 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="111"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-plastic02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-111"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="110"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-plastic01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-110"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/we-have-a-plastic-problem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Climate change</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/climate-change/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/climate-change/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Climate change is making oceans hotter, promoting acidification, and making it harder 
for marine life to breathe by reducing dissolved oxygen levels. We can reduce our own carbon 
footprint and help decelerate climate change by making smart choices about what we eat and 
how we travel.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What can you do?</h2>



<p>Our oceans are massive, they cover about 70% of the earth’s surface. Over 80% of the global<br>carbon cycle is circulated through the ocean. The ocean absorbs over 90% of excess heat from<br>greenhouse gas emissions over the past 50 years. Our planet can sustain life because of one<br>universally unique feature: the ocean. It produces half the oxygen we breathe, shapes our<br>weather and climates, provides food for all people and it has to be one of the places that foster<br>inspiration for anyone who lays eyes upon the vastness of the sea. But our marine ecosystems<br>are under attack and not only that but they are woefully underexplored and poorly understood.<br>Climate change is making oceans hotter, promoting acidification, and making it harder for<br>marine life to breathe by reducing dissolved oxygen levels. The ocean is home to millions of<br>marine species, some of who we have yet to even discover yet, this sea contributes to the<br>biodiversity of our planet. How are our actions impacting these lives?<br>We can reduce our own carbon footprint and help decelerate climate change by making smart<br>choices about what we eat and how we travel.<br>Climate change has been called the greatest challenge of our time. We need to make a change<br>and help our earth, our home, to heal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/climate-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shark Trip</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-trip/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-trip/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Our Trips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=174</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Want to swim with sharks? This trip is for you. We will see tiger sharks, 
hammerheads, lemons and occasionally whale sharks. Not only will you have a thrill 
experiencing silent, graceful beauties swim right by you, you will also learn about the 
importance of sharks. These top-level predators are necessary for a healthy ocean and help 
keep all the other species healthy as well .]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Adrenaline filled amazingness!</h2>



<p>Have you ever thought or dreamed about swimming with an apex predator? If you love sharks<br>this is a fin-tastic experience, you will be able to safely experience the awe and beauty of sharks<br>in the open ocean. Our expert team will keep tabs on you and ensure that you will be<br>completely safe.<br>The warm waters of the Caribbean are home to all kinds of sharks, this trip will allow you to see<br>many different species and the focus of this experience is to educate our guests and help to<br>dispel some of the common stereotypes that many people have when they think of sharks. The<br>waters off the Bahamas are known for nurse sharks, lemon sharks, reef sharks, tiger sharks, as<br>well as the iconic hammerhead shark, depending on the season. And when it comes to getting<br>close to these giant beauties, it pays to book a trip with an outfitter that knows what they’re<br>doing – that would be us!<br>Did you know more people die from taking selfies every year compared to shark attacks? What<br>about driving in a car? flying on a plane? Getting a soda from a vending machine? All of these<br>activities have a higher probability of being injured and/or killed when compared to shark<br>attacks.<br>In an effort to educate people on the true behavior of sharks — often calm and curious, not<br>aggressive — we offer educational experiences that allow people to see firsthand what<br>swimming with them is really like. Our hope is that these experiences may help to clear up any<br>misconceptions and inspire people to advocate for these amazing creatures.<br>Consider joining us for this incredible experience; what makes this trip special is the sheer<br>quantity of sharks; you can dive with as many as 50 at a time — a prospect that is at once both<br>intimidating and awe-inspiring. We will also see lots of other beautiful sea creatures and<br>pristine reefs .</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-11 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="148"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-shark05.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-148"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="147"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-shark04.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-147"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="146"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-shark03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-146"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="145"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-shark02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-145"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="144"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-shark01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-144"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-trip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Galapagos</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/galapagos/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/galapagos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Our Trips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This trip is an amazing opportunity to visit many of the islands in the archipelago. 
There is so much diversity and an abundance of wildlife that is found nowhere else on earth. 
We will spend 10 days with sharks, mantas, turtles, ocean iguanas and so much more. Learn 
about the unique conservation efforts and amazing animals found only in the Galapagos.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Diversity central!</h2>



<p>The Galapagos Islands are one of the world’s most spectacular Eden’s of biodiversity. This<br>archipelago is formed of a set of thirteen islands of volcanic origin and more than a hundred<br>islets and rocky outcrops. The Galapagos is a Natural World Heritage Site and Biosphere<br>Reserve, it is known to be the center of the observations and studies of Darwin’s for the<br>development of his “Theory of Evolution”.<br>These diverse volcanic islands are full of mystery and beauty, the wildlife along the Galapagos is<br>endemic to this area and really shows how diversity comes together to create fauna and flora<br>that only exists here. Exploring them is a dream and will forever impact how you see the world.<br>Island hopping one of the easiest and best alternatives to visit the Galapagos Islands, this allows<br>you to visit sites that spark your curiosity the most and witness the amazing and special wildlife.<br></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Why is Galapagos so special?</h3>



<p><br>Its exotic landscapes do not resemble other islands of the Pacific at all, they are comprised of<br>huge lava fields, rock formations, cactus forests and volcanic cones, the temperature is quite<br>arid. And this is exactly what makes this uninhabited place seem like it is from another time and<br>planet. Under the sea, there are underground craters and coral reefs, where an extraordinary<br>biological diversity is present. So much so they are also considered one of the seven<br>underwater wonders of the world and one of the most fascinating places in the planet to<br>perform deep sea diving.<br>We will share the rich history of the islands with you, both the geological and natural. One of<br>the first stops is a visit to the Charles Darwin Research Station, this research facility is full of an<br>extensive collection of preserved plant life along with the renowned breeding center. Here you<br>will encounter giant tortoises, land iguanas as well as numerous birds and plant life. Also, on<br>the itinerary we will visit many of the neighboring islands, each one its own eco-system and<br>home to unique animal and plant species. We will spend plenty of time in the water, exploring<br>the beautiful and wonderous scenes and observing wildlife at its finest.<br>Experiencing the Galapagos will strengthen the bond between you and nature. The islands are a<br>very unique place, and when you discover them, it is hard to forget your experiences there .</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-13 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="123"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-galapagos06.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-123"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="119"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-galapagos01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-119"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="800" height="400" data-id="122"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-galapagos05.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-122"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="121"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-galapagos03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-121"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="120"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-trip-galapagos02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-120"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/galapagos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
