<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Education &#8211; x-SITE</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/category/education/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:43:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/favicon.png</url>
	<title>Education &#8211; x-SITE</title>
	<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Shark Finning</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-finning/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-finning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Our apex predators, like sharks, play a critical role in regulating the eco-system - and 
they need our help! Many sharks are brutally slaughtered every day due to the inhuman 
process of finning. A third of shark species are already threatened with extinction.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Shark finning: a brutal practice</h2>



<p>Each year, millions of sharks are hunted down, only to have their fins sliced off and their bodies<br>are thrown back into the ocean often left to die an agonizing death. A shark is caught, pulled<br>onboard a boat, its fins are cut off, and the still-living shark is tossed back overboard to drown<br>or bleed to death. The wasteful, inhumane practice is done to satisfy a demand for shark fins,<br>which are in high demand for a luxury soup in Asia with reputable medicinal properties.<br>It has been proven that the shark fins have no nutritional value and are basically tasteless, the<br>flavor of the soup is derived from the broth. The fins are simply added for novelty and status</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is the threat to sharks?</h3>



<p>Finning is responsible for the death of about 100 million sharks every year, that is about 2-3<br>sharks being brutally killed every second! The exact numbers are unknown because in many<br>places and hauls aren’t accurately counted since shark finning is illegal.<br>Because sharks are at the top of the food chain and have few predators, they reproduce and<br>mature slowly. That means their numbers are slow to replenish when a population is<br>overfished. At the rate humans are going, we’re set to wipe out sharks entirely in as little as a<br>decade or so.<br>If sharks are completely eliminated we will have serious problems. Sharks are apex predators<br>and as such, they are invaluable for keeping the populations of everything else in the food chain<br>in balance. The oceans depend on sharks to keep the numbers of other fish and mammal<br>species in check by weeding out the sick, injured, and dying so that populations of fish stay<br>strong and healthy. Without sharks, the balance of the ocean’s food chain is in serious<br>jeopardy.<br>Shark finning is a cruel and dangerous practice, these vital animals are necessary to the<br>ecological balance of our oceans and are about to be wiped out completely</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What can you do?</h3>



<p>Educate yourself and others about how important sharks are</p>



<ul>
<li>Help spread the word about finning</li>



<li>Avoid all shark-related products and boycott businesses that sell and serve shark fins</li>



<li>Support marine protected areas</li>



<li>Urge your senator to support and pass the Shark Fin Sales Elimination Act of 2019<br>Sharks deserve to be swim free and are a vital part of the ocean ecosystem. Speak up for those<br>who can’t!</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="399" data-id="107"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-finning03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-107"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="106"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-finning02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-106"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="105"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-finning01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-105"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="397" data-id="108"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-finning04.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-108"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/shark-finning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We have a plastic problem</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/we-have-a-plastic-problem/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/we-have-a-plastic-problem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our oceans are facing growing challenges from pollution, habitat loss, development, 
and climate change.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Plastics are everyone’s problem</h2>



<p>Our oceans are facing growing challenges from pollution, habitat loss, development, and<br>climate change. The impact of plastic and micro-plastics on our seas is outrageous and<br>devastating for many species. Learn more about what you can do to stop it.<br>The ocean downstream from nearly every terrestrial location, it is the receiving body for much<br>of the plastic waste generated on land. Several million tons of debris end up in the world’s<br>oceans every year, and much of it is improperly discarded plastic litter.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Here are just a few chilling facts:</h3>



<ul>
<li>It is estimated that by 2050, oceans will carry more plastic mass than fish</li>



<li>Plastic waste kills up to 1 million sea birds, 100,000 sea mammals, marine turtles, and<br>countless fish each year</li>



<li>80% of all pollution in seas and oceans comes from land-based activities</li>



<li>It’s not just animals: people are consuming microplastics too. Ewwww!</li>



<li>A garbage truck’s worth of plastic is dumped into the ocean every single minute</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Take action right now!</h3>



<p>For a healthy planet, we need healthy oceans. Oceans cover 70% of the earth’s surface and they<br>are seriously under threat. We all need to do our part. Here are some things you can do right<br>now:</p>



<ul>
<li>Refuse single-use plastics</li>



<li>Only consume sustainable seafood</li>



<li>Speak up! Contact your representatives and let them know you are concerned.<br>The world is changing and finding a sustainable balance between the planet, people and profit<br>is challenging. Our vision is to raise awareness, encouraging more sustainable approaches and<br>choices. We need to help protect this fascinating environment and all the life that depends on it<br>to survive. Be the change, educate yourself and make smart choices, support businesses that<br>provide sustainable experiences and harvesting. Protect what you love!<br>We need everyone to help fight the plastic problem. Start now, before it’s too late.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-3 is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="111"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-plastic02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-111"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="400" data-id="110"  src="https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/post-plastic01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-110"/></figure>
</figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/we-have-a-plastic-problem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Climate change</title>
		<link>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/climate-change/</link>
					<comments>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/climate-change/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bahaa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/?p=176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Climate change is making oceans hotter, promoting acidification, and making it harder 
for marine life to breathe by reducing dissolved oxygen levels. We can reduce our own carbon 
footprint and help decelerate climate change by making smart choices about what we eat and 
how we travel.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What can you do?</h2>



<p>Our oceans are massive, they cover about 70% of the earth’s surface. Over 80% of the global<br>carbon cycle is circulated through the ocean. The ocean absorbs over 90% of excess heat from<br>greenhouse gas emissions over the past 50 years. Our planet can sustain life because of one<br>universally unique feature: the ocean. It produces half the oxygen we breathe, shapes our<br>weather and climates, provides food for all people and it has to be one of the places that foster<br>inspiration for anyone who lays eyes upon the vastness of the sea. But our marine ecosystems<br>are under attack and not only that but they are woefully underexplored and poorly understood.<br>Climate change is making oceans hotter, promoting acidification, and making it harder for<br>marine life to breathe by reducing dissolved oxygen levels. The ocean is home to millions of<br>marine species, some of who we have yet to even discover yet, this sea contributes to the<br>biodiversity of our planet. How are our actions impacting these lives?<br>We can reduce our own carbon footprint and help decelerate climate change by making smart<br>choices about what we eat and how we travel.<br>Climate change has been called the greatest challenge of our time. We need to make a change<br>and help our earth, our home, to heal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bahaamohamedmustafa.github.io/Trips-Blog/climate-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
